i signed up for this five-day challenge
on course creation with this woman named
grace lever
i've never heard about her before a
couple days ago when i signed up for
this course that started
yesterday but i just did the first task
this morning and in the first live video
she's talking about this um
financial freedom metric right what is
the amount of money you need to make per
month in order for you to
quit your job and and be financially
free
and she basically says if your number's
anything below 20 000 it needs to be
twenty thousand
at least and then she goes on to talk
about even when you make that twenty
when you make twenty thousand dollars
per month then you up it to fifty
thousand then you up it to a hundred
thousand
then you're making a million dollars a
year
that doesn't sound like freedom to me
that sounds like an addiction you're not
happy where you
are you need twenty thousand and yeah
that can set you financially free for
sure
but to say that's the minimum and then
to say that it has to keep increasing
and increasing
that is the definition of an addiction
and it is playing out in society
like we are addicts and is costing all
of us our planet
our health our happiness because
happiness is not achieved at a higher
and higher amount
because any money you achieve even if
you don't know this consciously you know
it subconsciously it costs the rest of
the world
you understand that there's no amount of
money you can have no bunker strong
enough
if our planet is failing and people are
starving they you are not safe and
secure you can't be there's no amount of
money that will make you safe and secure
therefore there's no amount of money
that can get you freedom there's no out
external metric that can give you true
freedom
it has to be hey how can i be happy
where i am
how can i live a more abundant life well
living my purpose in the world
why are we looking to the people with
the biggest addiction
to teach us how to also have the
addiction
and i get what they're saying like i
understand economics i understand that
if you're making twenty thousand
and you don't increase the price of your
course and now you're making fifty
thousand that means you've touched more
people's lives you've had more of an
impact
but that's not how they're selling it
right it's how much money do you need to
make
and then just keep increasing it and
increasing that if i said that about
absolutely anything else you would hear
it as an addiction
i really want a cat okay i have a cat i
just need two now just an extra cat okay
just one more cat one more cat
and pretty soon i'm the crazy cat lady
if i need a certain amount of caffeine
to get going in my day
and it's one cup of coffee and then in a
few months it's two cups
and then three cups and then four cups
you hear that as an addiction
so why when we talk about it with money
do we think of it as it
as something that is um
a goal we want to live up to i want to
be like her
i also want to need more and more and
more to succeed
if covet 19 teaches us nothing else
please let us
teach us that we are connected we are
one
we don't need to kumbaya be one we are
already one
our decisions what we do
impacts everybody else on this planet
and everything they do impacts
us we can solve problems and we can
create
true abundance by figuring out how to
live a good life
at let's say ten thousand dollars a
month and then figure out
how to live a better and better life for
less and less money because when we
figure that out
everybody unlocks that abundance not
just the person who's able to
earn from ten thousand to twenty
thousand to fifty thousand
i am sure i will be on for the rest of
the week being triggered by the
capitalist
course that i am in but that is today's
learning
why is money the socially acceptable
addiction
are there other ones i know power is
also kind of one that we somewhat are
acceptable by it's like oh i had 50
employees not 100 people telling me what
to do
i have more people following me but what
other dictions am i not seeing
that uh maybe i'm addicted to that i
can't see because those are the ones
i know i'm addicted to doing good in
this world and i'm okay with that
i also know i have actual addictions pot
in media
that i am in more control of than most
of the capitalists
and i can see what they're giving and
taking from my life and i'm figuring out
how to have them have less and less
impact
i'm not figuring out how to like have
more and more of them in my life
what am i not seeing what am i addicted
to and um
what are you addicted to are you looking
for more and more money
are you looking for more and more power
or can you be happy
with your current level and then figure
out how to be happier and happier at
this level
i invite you to look at who you prop up
in society
who do you look up to why are you
looking up to them what are the actual
qualities they possess that you want
because you probably already have them
that's why you're looking up to them if
you're not already
please subscribe please like this video
and i'll see you next time